Guide to the Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall Records, 1957-1992 (bulk 1991-1992
Duke University. University Archives
Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall records 1957-1992 (bulk 1991-1992)
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall.
0.2 linear feet Extent: 200 Items
Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall is a freshman dormitory on East Campus. Contains the records of activities of residents Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall. Types of materials include flyers, newsletters, agendas, notes, calendars, and damage reports. Major topics include residential living, Duke University, and social activities among students. The collection also contains accounting materials related to Addoms House. Materials date from 1957-1992 (bulk 1991-1992).
RL.01587
Language: Material in] English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1979 and 1995.
Historical Note
Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall opened in 1957 and is constructed of buff brick with limestone trim. Its name commemorates two outstanding scholars who began teaching at Duke with the founding of the Woman's College: Dr. Katherine Everett Gilbert and Dr. Ruth Margery Addoms. In 1930, the new West Campus opened and what had been the Trinity College campus (now East Campus) became the Woman's College.
Gilbert-Addoms, the largest dormitory on East Campus, is home to freshman undergraduate students. Gilbert-Addoms is located between Southgate and Blackwell Residence Halls.
Hte collection includes financial documents from Addoms House, including an account book as well as an undated constitution and records of the social activities of students living in Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall at Duke University from 1991-1992.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
College freshmen -- North Carolina -- Durham.; Duke University -- Students.; Duke University -- Students -- Social conditions.; Dormitories -- North Carolina -- Durham.; Residence and education.; Student housing -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Related Material
Alspaugh House Records
Duke University Archives
Association of Independent House Records
Duke University Archives
Baldwin Federation Records
Duke University Archives
Bassett Residence Hall Records
Duke University Archives
Brown House Records
Duke University Archives
Few Federation Records
Duke University Archives
Giles House Records
Duke University Archives
House CC Records
Duke University Archives
Jarvis House Records
Duke University Archives
Mirecourt House Records
Duke University Archives
Pegram House Records
Duke University Archives
Warwick House Records
Duke University Archives
Wilson House Records
Duke University Archives
York House Records
Duke University Archives
Bibliography
Willimon. William H. We Work Hard, We Play Hard: A Report for the President, and the Provost, and the Vice President for Student Life of Duke University.,
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Account Ledger, 1957/1958-1967/1968 (Addoms House) (Box 1)
  - Constitution of Addoms House, undated
  - Budget Reports, 1957-1968 (Addoms House)
  - Alison Stuebe for President fliers, 1991
  - Council of Freshman Presidents, 1991-1992
  - Damage reports, 1991-1992
  - Evaluations, 1992
  - House Council, 1991
  - Newsletters, 1991-1992
  - Programming, 1991-1992
  - Social activities, 1991-1992